





ANDRÉS CAMILO ÁLVAREZ MONTOYA

WHO AM I?

Python developer Chemical Engineer and PhD in Chemical Engineering currently working as a full time Python developer to maintain a web page. Have a great ability to apply new knowledge to other fields and a great adaptability to new jobs environments. My key strength are to learn quickly and auto didactically by watching videos or reading books and to display ability to research new topics.

Skills

PythonSQL

· Django · HTML

· Git/GitHub · CSS

· Numpy · JavaScript

· Pandas · AWS

Matplotlib
 Heroku

· Scipy · Matlab

EXPERIENCE

5/2021-current Full-time

Python Developer

Globant

I collaborated to maintain the back end development of a CMS written in django for a logistic company. I have made contributions to the project to fulfill constantly changing business requirements. I wrote algorithms to update the images hosted in Azure of several sites to improve performance and reduce size of them.

Python / Django / MySQL / Azure

9/2018-4/2019 Full-time

Internship Researcher

TU-Freiberg, Germany

I used a kinetic model written in Matlab for the fitting of experimental data of the kinetics of adsorption process for the reduction of greenhouse gases from diesel engines. I developed a repository of the plots using Python (Matplotlib, NumPy, SciPy, and Pandas). I attained well adaptation to the German working environment.

Python / Matlab / LaTex

8/2015-8/2018 Full-time

Researcher

Universidad de Antioquia

I calculated several mathematical problems (NumPy, SciPy), plotted results (Matplotlib) and analyzed data (pandas) for the reduction of nitrogen oxides from diesel engines. I developed scripts to calculate reagents amounts, model data, and process large files of data. I oversaw the gases inventory.

Python / Matlab / LaTex

6/2011-12/2011 Full-time

Research Assistant

CENIVAM

I performed chemical reactions, collected data, and modeled the kinetics of the allylic oxidation of an essential oil (α -pinene) for fine chemistry.

Matlab / Office

EDUCATION

2015-2020 PhD in Chemical Engineering

Universidad de Antioquia

Research on the reduction gases (NO, NO_2) from diesel engine exhausts. I used Python libraries to calculate several mathematical problems (NumPy, SciPy), to plot results (Matplotlib) and to analyze data (pandas). Writing of a manuscript in LaTeX.

2012-2014 MSc in Materials

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

Production and characterization of titanium dioxide thin films for photovoltaic cells. Computations using Matlab®.

2005-2011 Chemical Engineering

Universidad de Antioquia

Simulation of the selective non catalytic reduction of nitrogen oxide using Chemkin ${\mathbb B}$. Programming in Matlab ${\mathbb B}$ of chemical engineering equipment, such as storage vessel, distillation column, and heat exchanger.

COURSES

2021	CS50x: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science	edX
2020	AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native	Coursera
2020	Google IT Automation with Python (courses 1, 2, 3, and 4)	Coursera
2020	Django for Everybody Specialization	Coursera
2020	Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach	Coursera
2020	Introduction to Web Development	Coursera
2020	Neural Networks and Deep Learning, and Improving Deep Neural Networks	Coursera
2020	Python Classes and Inheritance	Coursera
2015	Programming for Everybody (Python)	Coursera
2014	An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python	Coursera
2010	Informática: Diseño de Bases de Datos en SQL	SENA Virtual

SOME OF MY PROJECTS

2021	Web application that show some engineering-related problems that let the user change parameters to see how they affect the result Click here to see. Python, Django, Heroku, NumPy, Matplotlib, pandas, SciPy
2021	Web application for calculating the fortnight salary according to Colombian legislation. Click here to see. HTML, CSS, Javascript, Netlify
2020	Final project for the Django for Everybody Specialization on Coursera. Click here to see. Python, Django, SQL, pythonanywhere
2020	Modeling of the Tri-reforming reactions (minimization of the Gibbs free energy). Click here to see. NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib

LANGUAGES REFERENCES HOBBIES

Spanish: native. English: C1 (EF SET 67/100), B2.

Portuguese: advanced (learned in Brazil).

Available upon request. Riding bike, playing soccer,

and tennis. Reading.